

Matthias Benkort

Passionate Software Engineer

Q August 1992 - 25 y.o.

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

(NL) +31 657208274

@ matthias.benkort@gmail.com

KtorZ

matthias-benkort-47186a57

S matthias.benkort

https://ktorz.github.io

About me ———

Functional Programming & Philosophy enthusiast. Programming elegant solutions for puzzling problems has been my passion since I am ten. Besides, cooking, bouldering, exploring music, and drinking tea are the current pillars of my personal well-being.

Skills ———

JavaScript

Haskell, PureScript, Elm

Python, Java, Go

* MongoDB * Redis * Git * Docker *

Values

I value others' opinions and help.

I proudly do because I enjoy doing it.

I learn, question, adapt and evolve constantly.

I base my decisions upon rational arguments and researches.

I keep my own expectations always higher. I share and I communicate transparently.

I eat my cheese with a Baguette.

Experience

2017	Lead Software Engineer [Freelancer] Dimebox - The Netherlands
	Automating Machine Learning with Haskell & Python in order to dy-
	namically classify transactions (e.g. frauds).

2017 Software Engineer [Freelancer] Chordify - The Netherlands
Turning legacy *PHP* into a modern and reliable *Haskell* API.

2017 Software Engineer [Freelancer] TruQu - The Netherlands
Developing tools and open-source libraries using Elm & PureScript

2016-2017 Software Engineer Dimebox - The Netherlands

Solving problems in the payment industry by designing and building a white-label, easy-to-integrate payment technology with *Node.js*.

2016 Software Engineer The Things Network - The Netherlands

Developing the first global, distributed and open network for the In-

ternet of Things in Go.

2015-2016 Full-Stack Developer The Smiths - The Netherlands

Crafting mobile, web and backend applications using cross-platform *JavaScript* technologies, promoting open-source and knowledge

sharing.

2014 Software Engineer [Intern]

Developing deployment and testing tools in Python for a Java dis-

tributed system to help the team increase its productivity.

2013-2014 Tutor Acadomia - France

Listening, giving advice and accompaniment of students from school to high school in Mathematics, Physics and Computer Science.

Education

2010-2015 Master Degree

Computer Science Applied Mathematics

France

Programming Linear Algebra
Semantic Differential Calculus

Architecture Graphs

Specifications Statistics & Probabilities

Concurrency Optimization
Networks Logic

Projects

since 2015 Maintainer & Translator of the Mostly Adequate Guide to FP. 2014 Development of an in-browser game inspired by a succinct demo	since 2017	Port of the IndexedDB & Web Workers APIs to PureScript
 2015-2016 Organizer & occasional speaker of the Titanium Amsterdam meet since 2015 Maintainer & Translator of the Mostly Adequate Guide to FP. 2014 Development of an in-browser game inspired by a succinct demo 	2017	Design & Implementation of a compiler NoSQL $ ightarrow$ SQL.
since 2015 Maintainer & Translator of the Mostly Adequate Guide to FP. 2014 Development of an in-browser game inspired by a succinct demo	2016-2017	Organizer & occasional speaker of the Elm Amsterdam meetups.
2014 Development of an in-browser game inspired by a succinct demo	2015-2016	Organizer & occasional speaker of the Titanium Amsterdam meetups
	since 2015	Maintainer & Translator of the Mostly Adequate Guide to FP.
2013-2014 Web apps development as Student-entrepreneur	2014	Development of an in-browser game inspired by a succinct demo.
	2013-2014	Web apps development as Student-entrepreneur